Hello.
你們好
I come from outside the wall,
我來自圍牆之外
where we have all but destroyed each other.
在那兒 人們相互摧殘
We designed you city as an experiment.
把你們的城市設計成實驗室
And we believe it is the only way to recover the humanity we have lost.
是因為堅信這是重拾人性的唯一途徑
And we created Factions to ensure peace.
我們創建了派系來維護和平
But we believe there will be those among you
但我們也相信 你們當中肯定
who will transcend these factions,
有人能超越這些派系
these will be the Divergent.
他們將是分歧者
They are the true purpose of this experiment,
是這場實驗的真正目的
they are vital to humanity survival.
對人類的存亡至關重要
If you are watching this now, then at least one of you is proof
如果你們正在看這段視頻 說明至少有一個人
that our experiment has succeeded.
證明了實驗室成功的
The time has come
是時候從
for you to emerge from your isolation and rejoin us.
你們封閉的城市裡走出來了
On Evelyn's orders: This gate is now closed!
奉伊芙琳之令 馬上關閉城門
We've allowed you to believe that you’re the last of us,
我們曾讓你們相信自己是最後的倖存者
but you’re not.
其實不是
Mankind waits for you with hope, beyond the Wall.
其他人類正在圍牆外滿懷希望地等待著你們
ALLEGIANT
分歧者3：忠誠世界
We're almost there.
我們快到了
Yeah, I'm right behind you.
對 我在你後面
What are you, afraid of heights?
我說你不會恐高吧
No. Who told you that?
不 誰跟你說的
Sometimes when I look past the wall,
有時候我朝圍牆外面看
I think that I can see something out there.
感覺自己能看到外面的東西
Do you?
你呢
No. I don't.
我 看不到
Maybe you need to look harder.
也許你得看仔細點兒
I am looking.
我正看著呢
I'm just not seeing what you see.
可還是什麼都看不到
When it's right in front of your face, you will.
如果在眼前 你就看到了
You sure we're going to do this?
我們真的要離開嗎
Yeah.
對
People of Chicago,
芝加哥的全體公民
I know you are curious about what's beyond the wall,
我知道你們很好奇圍牆外有什麼
but sometimes walls are there to protect us.
但有的時候圍牆是在保護我們
Remember, the founders were the ones who divided us into Factions.
記住 正式那些創建者把我們劃分成了若干派系
So, until we know their intentions, the wall must stay closed.
所以在我們不知道他們的真實目的前城門必須關閉
Jeanine is dead.
珍寧已經死了
Today, we begin the trials of her conspirators.
今天 我們要開始審判她的同謀者以此紀念芝加哥翻開了新的一頁
Put the traitors on trial, close down the gate.
審判叛徒 關閉城門
Didn't take her long to make the same mistakes as Jeanine.
沒想到 她這麼快就走上了珍寧的老路
I need to talk to her.
我得跟他談談
I still think I can bring her around.
我想我能勸他回頭
But that doesn't change anything, right?.
但那改變不了任何事
No.
不
I need you to get somethings for me.
我要你幫我弄點兒東西
Just this?
就這個
You sure you don't want the sun and moon as well?
確定不再摘個太陽月亮什麼的
- I know it's a lot. - It's impossible.
我知道這很困難   簡直是不可能
- So? - So, I'll make it happen.
所以  所以只有我能搞定
Well. Hello, ladies.
你們好 女士們
Where are we going? Can I come?
要去哪兒  能一起嗎
- Give it up, Peter. - Why so hostile!
滾遠點 皮特   太不友好了
There's no faction. We can be friends, right?
派系都沒了 我們能成朋友了  對嗎
Can't we all just get along?
難道就不能相親相愛嗎
Tris.
翠絲
Your should be up there with all the other leaders of the city.
你應該上去跟其他領導者在一起
No, it's not me. I don't want to make the rules.
不 我可不想  去制定什麼規矩
Great leaders don't seek power, they're called by necessity.
偉大的領導者從不追逐權利 他們被社會需求所召喚
They need you.
人們需要你
Look at me! Look at me, traitor!
看著我  你這個叛徒
- You're going to die in there! - Back up.
後退 準備好去死了嗎  後退
You're going to die in there!
準備去死了嗎
Move!
快走
Sit tight.
待在這兒
We all find ourselves on new ground.
我們都在新環境中找到了自己
I dedicated my life to seeking the truth, but under Jeanine, it passed me by.
我畢生的志願就是追尋真相  但珍寧卻讓我錯過了它
And for that, I humbly apologize.
為此 我真誠想諸位道歉
But my personal failure has only strengthened my resolve to make things right.
但是我失敗的教訓 更堅定了我糾正自己錯誤的決心
While the Faction of Candor may no longer exist,
即使現在誠實派不復存在了
I want everyone to know that I will not stop leading the pursuit of honesty,
我也想讓大家知道 我不會停下追尋真相的腳步
as we rebuild our city.
讓我們攜起手來 重建家園
- Yay! - Yay!
好 好
Let the trials begin! Justice will be done!
審判現在開始  讓我們來伸張正義
- Yay! - Yay!
好 好
Here.
來吧
May the truth set you free.
願真相讓你解脫
There's no doubt, Max, that you helped Jeanine take over Chicago,
毫無疑問 你協助珍寧接管了芝加哥
and exert brutal control over it's citizens.
對人們進行了殘忍的控制
So, my only question to you is this.
我唯一想問的就是你覺得
Did you feel justified in murdering people in support of her regime?
屠殺人民去支持她的政權是否正確
Absolutely.
當然正確
People are sheep. They need a shepherd to guide them.
人民是綿羊 他們需要牧羊人引導
And when they resist, they're slaughtered.
如果他們反抗 就該被殺
Monster.
We should slaughter you!
我們應該殺了你
Kill him! Kill him!
殺了他 殺了他
- Kill him! - Don't kill him!
殺了他 不要殺他
- Let him live! - Kill him!
別殺他   殺了他
- Let him live! - Kill him now!
Rise above it.
理智點
You can't do this, stop it!
你們不能這樣做 快停下來
Let him live! We're better than this!
別殺他 我們跟那些殺人犯不一樣
Rise above it.
理智點
Jeanine!
珍寧
Jeanine is dead!
珍寧已經死了
Let's not keep her spirit alive.
我們不能再重蹈覆轍了
- Kill him! - Let him live!
殺了他 別殺他
What are you going to do? They need an answer.
現在怎麼辦 得給他們個交代
This is an execution.
這是一場殺戮
No. This is a trial.
不  這是一場審判
And I yield, to the wishes of the people.
我服從全體公民的意願
It is time, that we break from the past!
是時候打破歷史的牢籠
- Yay! - Yay!
好
You need to die!
殺了他
I don't want to die.
我還不想死
Neither did your sheep.
你殺的人也不想
Yeah.
太棒了
There was a time I would have said: I leave you with love, not malice.
過去我說過  我願你們活在愛裡 而不是恨裡
That time has passed.
看來過去已經過去了
- Kill her! - Traitor!
Kill her! Kill her!
Traitor!
Get out! Out! Get out! Out!
出去
Get out! Out!
Beatrice! I'm sorry!
碧翠絲 對不起
You incited a mob. Good luck controlling them.
你煽動了民眾 但願你能掌控得住
Beatrice, please! Don't let them kill me!
碧翠絲 求你了 別讓他們殺了我
Beatrice! No!
碧翠絲  不
Beatrice!
碧翠絲
What the hell did you think you're doing? We need to show a united front.
你知道你在做什麼嗎 我們得表現得團結一致
Especially, since Tris refuses to stand with us.
尤其是翠絲拒絕跟我們同一陣營之後
- I'm not going to tell Tris what to do. - Well, you need to try!
我不會告訴她 她該幹什麼  你得試著跟她說
Do you really think that you can stop people leaving this city?
你真的認為自己能阻止人們離開這座城市嗎
The wall's on total lock down, my soldiers have orders.
城門現在已經鎖上了 我的士兵們聽從我的
No one gets out.
沒人能出去
Why did you go to war with Jeanine,
你為什麼要跟珍寧開戰
if you were just going to become her?
難道只是想變成她
Leaders need to make tough decisions to protect their people.
領導者們為了保護人民需要做出艱難的決定
You'll understand that when you take over from me.
等你繼承了我的位置自然就會明白了
I'm doing this for you.
我這都是為了你
You know, it might not be the best time to leave.
現在可能不是離開的最佳時機
I know, but we can't be here for every fight.
那也不能待在這兒解決所有衝突
And the message said to come out and meet the rest of the world .
資訊裡也說要走出去面對新世界
Yet, we know absolutely nothing about the people who sent it.
可我們對傳遞資訊的人一無所知
Aren't you curious to find out?
那你就不想把她找出來嗎
What about our home?
我們的家園怎麼辦
I don't think our home exist any more.
我覺得我們的家園已經不復存在了
Maybe the way to help Chicago is climb beyond the wall.
也許走出去反而能夠幫到芝加哥
What if there's nothing out there? What If there is nothing left?
可萬一外面什麼都沒有 荒蕪一片呢
I can live with that if you are with me, but I can not live without trying.
只要你在我就能活下去 但你必須得讓我試一試
You know, it's Caleb's trial tomorrow.
你知道明天要審凱萊布吧
Yeah, I know.
是 我知道
I don't owe him anything.
可我沒覺得有什麼欠他的
No. No, you don't.
沒錯  你不欠他
I'm going to deal with this one.
我來處理這個人
Do you think I'm asking your permission?
你覺得我是在請求你嗎
No, please. No, Four. No!
不 求你了 老四 不要
Four. Four.
老四 求你了
Please don't kill me! I'm sorry!
別殺我  對不起
Four, I'm sorry!
老四 對不起
You tried to kill your own sister, Caleb. You brought this on yourself.
連自己親妹妹都想殺  你這是作死
I'm sorry, for everything.
對不起  我向你道歉
Come on. We're going up.
快點 我們上去
Come on. Come on.
快點
- Beatrice? - Walk slowly.
碧翠絲 慢點兒走
Hey!
嘿
All Erudite prisoners are suppose to be locked in the cages.
所有博學派的犯人都應關在牢裡
Stop!
站住
I can handle this one myself.
我自己能處理這個人
Bring him in!
帶他們進來
You can come out now, Caleb.
你現在能出來了
Thank you, Four. Thank you.
謝謝你 老四 謝謝
Don't thank me. It's your sister's idea.
不用謝我 是你妹妹的主意
You saved me?
你救了我
It's what you do for family.
這才是家人該做的
Get in the car.
上車吧
I knew it.
我就知道
Hey, partners.
嘿 夥計們
What are you doing, Peter? Get out of here.
你們在這幹什麼 皮特 離開這兒
Yes, that's what I'm doing, I'm getting out of here.
沒錯 我正準備要離開這兒
Look, I don't want to be here when your crazy mom
聽著 在你媽媽肆意妄為的時候我可不想留在這兒
goes around killing everybody who used to work for Jeanine, okay?
她會整死所有為珍寧做過事的人
Look, I can join you guys or I could...
聽著 要麼現在就讓我加入你們要麼我就
Yell: Help! Help! Help! They're getting away!
大喊 救命 他們要跑了 嚷嚷什麼 消停會行嗎
Get in the car, Peter. Get in the car.
上車 皮特 上車
- That's what I'm saying. - Get in the car.
就等這句話呢  上車
Thank you.
謝謝
What's up, Caleb?
還好嗎 凱萊布
Yeah!
沒錯
We want the truth!
我們要聽真相
He's dead. Yeah. Hurry up and kill him.
他死定了 對 快殺了他
Justice for all!
伸張正義
You do have a plan, right?
你已經有計劃了是吧
I didn't hear anything about a prisoner transfer.
我沒接到任何轉移犯人的通知
Well, you're hearing it from me.
我剛剛通知過你
Let me see your movement order.
請出示轉移令
I got it! Right here!
在這兒呢 在我這兒
I got everything. So, open the gate.
這是轉移令 把門打開
One more, come on. Come on, one more. Yeah!
再來一個 快點兒 好 愛德格
Tobias Eaton took Caleb Prior out of his cage.
托比亞斯•伊頓把凱萊布•普勒爾帶走了
Come on. Let's go, now.
快點兒 我們走 快
Come on! Let's do some more!
快點兒 再審幾個
You a statue?
你是雕塑嗎
Open the gate.
快開門
Have they come through here?
他們從這兒走的
Let's get out of here.
我們離開這兒
They're getting away.
他們跑了
Tobias Eaton is abetting Caleb Prior's escape. That makes him a traitor.
托比亞斯•伊頓帶著凱萊布•普勒爾逃跑了 他也成了反叛者
Shoot to kill.
殺了他
No body goes over that wall. We have our orders.
任何人不得翻越圍牆 這是命令
You Ready?
好了嗎
Yeah.
好了
Not the same as reading in the books, huh?
跟書本上學的不太一樣
okay, coast is clear.
好了 沒有危險
It's time to see what's out there.
是時候走出去了
Okay. On me.
好的 跟緊我
Shit. Release now!
該死 發射 抓鉤
I got him.
我去幫他
I'm sorry, Four.
抱歉 老四
Come on. Come on.
快點
- Ahhhh! - CHRISTINA !
- I'm okay. - That part of the plan, Stiff?
沒事 這也是計畫的一部分
Evelyn electrified the fence.
伊芙琳給圍欄通了電
We did it.
我們成功了
Tori.
托莉
Tori. Tori! Tori!
Okay, Tori.
天哪 托莉
Come on, we got to go. Come on!
快點兒 我們得離開這兒
No! Tori!
不 托莉
Tori.
托莉
Get in the car!
上車
Alright, let's go.
好了 我們走
Come on. This way!
快點兒 這邊
Holy shit.
我的天哪
What happened here?
這兒發生了什麼
Didn't exactly sent out a welcome committee for you, Stiff.
根本沒為你準備歡迎儀式 僵屍人
Shut up, Peter.
閉嘴  皮特
Humanity welcomes you with hope. What humanity?
人類滿懷希望地歡迎你們 人在那兒呢
This hole looks radioactive.
這個水坑看起來好像又放射性
Or at least it was so in the last 200 years.
至少得有200年了
Meaning what exactly?
這能說明什麼問題
Somebody seriously messed up the world.
有人毀了這個世界
Shit.
該死
Great. Now the sky is bleeding.
真給力 天空都流血了
This way!
這邊走
Come on, let's go!
快點兒  我們走
Now, come on.
跟緊了
This is fun. I'm glad we did this.
真好玩 把自己給玩了
What if there's nothing else out there?
萬一什麼都沒有呢
There has to be.
一定會有的
I'm scared.
我害怕
Yeah, I think that's a good thing.
我想  這是正常反應
You guys hear that?
聽到了嗎
- It's an engine. - Someone's coming for us.
是引擎 有人來找我們了
- It's Edgar. Go, go! - Come on!
是愛德格 快跑 快
Go, go! Turn back, go!
快 快跑 那邊跑
Hollis! No! Hollis!
霍利斯 不 霍利斯
Who, what is this?
天哪 這是 這是什麼
Don't be afraid, there's nothing to worry about.
別害怕 不用擔心
You're safe now.
你們現在安全了
Welcome, Four.
歡迎你 老四
Tris Prior, it's an honor to meet you.
普勒爾很榮幸見到你
How do you know our names?
你怎麼知道我名字
What the?
什麼情況
Oh oh.
Welcome to the future. We've been waiting for you.
歡迎來到你們的未來 我們一直在等你們
Our plasma globes will protect you from the toxicity.
等離子球會把你們和有毒的環境隔離開
Hey.
嘿
- We're going to be okay. - Yeah.
我們現在安全了  對
Look.
看啊
This is incredible.
不可思議
This is insane!
簡直太瘋狂了
Get out.
天哪 超贊
It's Tris.
她是翠絲
Welcome, to the Bureau of Genetic Alter. My name is Matthew.
歡迎你們來到基因福利局 我是馬修
Now, let's get you into decontamination.
現在 你們將被送進淨化區 他們從芝加哥來
That's her, Beatrice Prior. She made it.
那個就是她 翠絲普勒爾 她終於來了
There's nothing to worry about.
什麼都不用擔心
You're being decontaminated from the toxins which plague our world.
它會把你們身上沾染的 我們世界的毒素清洗掉
Please remove your clothes and place them in the incineration hatch.
請把你們的衣服脫了 然後丟進焚化爐
Please step forward.
上前一步
Place your feet on the mark.
站在標記上
You're clean.
搞定了
Please place your arm into the tube in the wall.
請把手放進牆上的孔道裡
There's nothing to worry about, Tris.
不用有任何顧慮 翠絲
Please place your arm into the tube.
請把手放進孔道裡
I've never felt so clean in my life.
這輩子都沒這麼乾淨過
That was the best weird shower I've ever had.
這是我洗過的最奇怪的澡了
A little cold thou.
有點兒冷 但是
Hey, yours is different.
你的紋身不一樣
Why they are all different?
為什麼都不一樣
Hello, and welcome to the Bureau of Genetic Welfare.
你們好 歡迎各位光臨基因福利局
In the early part of the 21st century, scientists first discovered a way to map
在21世紀上半時 科學家們首次發現並繪製了
then edit the human genome.
改變人類基因組的方法 你可以選擇健康
You can choose to settle from "merely adequate" or you can choose "excellent".
你能選擇保持自身的基因組 也能選擇改善它們
A genetic solution puts you in control of your life.
基因解決方案讓你可以掌控自己的生命
So, why just hope for a better future, when you can choose perfection?
為什麼不期待一個更美好的未來 當你有機會選擇完美時
Choose Perfexia.
請選擇蒲飛霞
But, what started as an attempt to erase humanity's fault,
但是正如試圖清楚人類缺陷一樣
almost erased humanity itself.
人性也幾乎被抹殺了
Genetic modification deepened the rifts between people.
基因改造加劇了人們之間的分歧
And as they got more entrenched, the world began to tear apart,
當矛盾越來越深 世界便開始四分五裂
until humanity cross a line, from which it could never return.
人類也因無法恢復原始基因而變得無可挽救
In the ashes of civilization,
在這片文明的廢墟上
a small group of genetically unmodified individuals established the "BUREAU OF GENETIC WELFARE."
一小群基因未被改造的人建立了你們今天所在的這個基因福利局 “基因福利局”
here in Chicago's O'Hare Airport.
在這兒 芝加哥的奧黑爾機場
Our mission is to oversee a grand experiment
我們的任務是監控一項重要的實驗
to purify the human genome.
其目的就是淨化人類的基因組
That experiment is the city of Chicago.
而實驗室就是芝加哥市
Your participation in the Bureau's work means you are now the guardians of the future.
你們參與到了基因局的工作 就意味著成為了人類未來的守護者
Your destiny begins today.
你們的使命從今天開始
Now. Please follow me.
現在請跟我來
What's an airport?
機場是什麼鬼
Life in the Bureau can be demanding.
在這兒生活限制很多
The work is worth every sacrifice.
但是我們的值得為此付出
We don't have all the resources we would like of course,
基因局並不是要什麼就有什麼
but I think you'll find your accommodations more than adequate
但足以滿足你們的基本生活
- Whoa. - Wow.
哇
They're in person, here.
他們是真人啊
- Who are they? - We bring them in from the Fringe.
他們是誰  從邊界帶回來的
Get them healthy. Give them a second chance.
等他們治好了 就能活下去了
- Hi, Four. - Hi, Four.
老四
Hi, Four.
Now they know who we are.
他們怎麼知道我們的
The experiment is the entire focus of the Bureau.
實驗室是整個基因局的焦點
Our Surveillance Technology is centuries ahead of anything you know in Chicago.
我們的監控技術領先你們芝加哥幾個世紀
They grown up watching you.
他們看著你們長大
Nothing creepy about that.
你可嚇著我們了
You have to forgive everyone for staring, but...
請原諒所有人都盯著你們看  但..
your arrival is the most exciting event some of us have ever known.
你們的到來對我們來說是件大事
Welcome to your new home.
歡迎來到新家
Where's Four? Did you hurt him?
老四在哪裡 傷著他了嗎
I told you I wanted them unharmed.
我說過我要他們幾個毫髮無損
He went with them. Willing.
跟他們走了 是自願的
- But he's alive. - Did you hear what I'm saying?
他還活著嗎 你沒聽懂嗎
He betrayed you.
他背叛了你
No...
不
- It's just love. - He's your son.
都是因為愛情  他是你兒子
He should be loyal. I'm loyal!
他應該忠誠  像我這樣
Yes, you are!
沒錯 你很忠誠
So, rest up. I need you ready to fight.
去休息吧 我要你做好戰鬥準備
What do you think?
想什麼呢
I think they've been studying us for 200 years and we need to catch up.
他們研究了我們200年 我們得迎頭趕上
We're going to give it a chance, right?
我們得抓住機會對嗎
Yep, of course we are.
沒錯 完全正確
I wish we were alone.
真想單約你
Excuse me. The Director's ready to see you.
打擾一下 我們頭兒說要見你
No, I'm sorry. I mean Tris, alone.
不 對不起 我說的是翠絲
We can't go together?
不能一起去嗎
Since you were the one who opened the box which invited you here.
因為你是那個打開盒子的人
The Director would like to thank your personal.
所以我們頭兒想要親自感謝你
I'll see you later.
一會兒見
- Clothes. - Thanks.
衣服 謝謝
This way.
這邊請
Go ahead. Put your wrist under the scanner.
來吧 手腕放在掃描器上
Access granted.
允許 進入
Pure.
純淨
I just never imagined the world to be this big.
我從沒想過還有次芝加哥大的地方
Chicago is just one of 50 major cities that used to exist
在北美 芝加哥只是過去50個大城市中的一個
on this continent along.
除此之外
Beyond that is, oceans and more land than you can imagine.
還有一望無際的還有和廣闊的大陸
But it's all like this now?
現在都變樣了
Yeah.
對
All except for Providence.
除了普羅維登斯
Which is why what we're doing here is so important, Tris.
所以我們在這兒做的事非常重要 翠絲
Hello.
你好
- You must be director. - Oh, please call me David.
你一定是頭兒了   拜託 叫我大衛
It is a pleasure to finally meet you.
很高興我終於見到你了
You must have so many questions.
你一定有很多疑問
I'm a bit overwhelmed. I'm still processing it and all.
我有點兒不知所措 我還在試著理解
Oh. Tris, I know you.
翠絲  我瞭解你
I watched you being born.
你一出生我就在觀察你
I saw the love that your mother and father had for you.
我看到了你父母對你的愛
I watched a little girl have a happy childhood and grow into a courageous young woman
看到了一個擁有幸福童年的小姑娘是如何成長為一名
capable of making choices.
勇敢而果斷的女孩
Dauntless. Defying Jeanine.
如入無畏派 推翻珍寧
Saving Chicago.
拯救芝加哥
To your people, you are a divergent.
對人民你是分歧者
To the Council, you're a freak.
對委員會 你是怪胎
To me, you are a a miracle.
對我 你就是個奇跡
David. are you-are you aware what's happening in Chicago right now?
大衛 你注意到芝加哥現在發生的事了嗎
Of Course. Yes.
注意到了 當然
The people at Erudite really made a mess of things,
博學派的人真是夠可以的
but I don't want your to worry about that.
但我不想你為這些擔心
Restoring order in Chicago is as important to me as it is to you.
恢復芝加哥的秩序對你和我都很重要
It's the only way to save the "damaged".
這是拯救缺陷者的唯一辦法
What is the "damaged".
什麼是缺陷者
The genetic alterations had disastrous consequences.
基因改造產生了嚴重的後果
Too brave and you're cruel. Too peaceful and you're passive.
太勇敢會變得殘忍 太平和會變得懦弱
Too smart, and you'll lose compassion, like your brother.
太聰明會變得冷酷 就像你哥哥
- Caleb's "damaged"? - Yes.
凱萊布是缺陷者嗎  沒錯
For nearly 200 years,
近200年來
the greatest scientific minds have live here to test a theory.
頂尖的科學家們在這兒驗證一個理論
If we can rescue genetically damaged people
如果我們能把邊界地帶
from the toxic environment in the Fringe.
有毒環境中的基因缺陷者
and put them in a safe place like Chicago,
放在像芝加哥這樣安全的城市裡
then perhaps over time, man's genetic material would heal itself.
也許久而久之 人們的基因就能治癒自己
Return to its original form.
這樣就可以回到原來的樣子了
And I'm one of those people?
我就是其中的一個
You're the only one.
你是唯一的一個
That doesn't- That doesn't make any sense
你這麼說沒道理 我是說
Four is divergent. There's lot of divergences.
老四也是分歧者 還有很多分歧者
Not divergent, Tris. Pure.
不是分歧者  翠絲  是純淨者
You're genetically "pure". The rest are still "damaged".
你是基因純淨者  其他人都是缺陷者
- Four? - Damaged.
老四呢  缺陷者
Not as much as Caleb, but "damaged".
不像凱萊布那麼嚴重  但也是缺陷者
If we can understand what made you,
如果我們能知道是什麼治癒了你
maybe we can use that knowledge to help the "damaged".
也許我們就能幫助其他的缺陷者了
What does this have to do with Chicago?
但這跟芝加哥有什麼關係
I answer to the Council.
我會向委員會彙報
They're the ones who ultimately determine our fate.
他們是最終決定我們命運的人
Yours and mine.
你們的和我的
I'm going to bring you with me to Providence to meet them.
我準備帶你去見他們
When they see that it's possible, that you were possible,
當他們看見這是有可能的 你就是那個可能性
it will change everything.
一切都會改變
I understand it's hard to take my word for it.
我明白我的話很難的到信任
But, if you don't believe me, believe your mother.
但是若果你不相信我 就相信你母親
My mother?
我母親
Your mother, Natalie, wasn't born in Chicago.
你母親納塔莉不是出生在芝加哥
She was born in the Fringe and rescued by the Bureau.
她出生在邊界地帶 然後被基因局救了
No, that's impossible.
不 這根本不可能
See for yourself.
眼見為實
What are these?
這是什麼
They're your mother's memory tabs.
這是你目前的記憶卡
With them, you can watch the world through her eyes.
有了這些你就能通過她的眼睛去看世界
What do I do?
我該怎麼做
Place one on each temple.
在太陽穴上各放一枚
Natalie, come on!
納塔莉 快點兒
I'm not Natalie.
我不是納塔莉
We need to hide! Come on!
我們得藏起來  快點兒
They're coming! Run!
他們來了 快跑
The Fringers!
是邊界掠奪者
Run!
快跑
The Fringers!
是邊界掠奪者
I'm not Natalie.
我不是納塔莉
Natalie, no!
納塔莉 不
No!
不
Bureau soldiers!
基因局的士兵
Left! Flank left!
左邊  左翼包抄
Keep right! Keep right! Keep right!
打右邊
We're taking you to the Bureau. You're safe.
我們帶你到基因局  你安全了
You don't have to be afraid anymore.
不用再擔驚受怕了
- How many more did you save today? - Not enough.
今天又救了多少個孩子  不夠多
We never get enough.
永遠都不夠多
Chicago has got to work, David. It's the only hope for us.
芝加哥必須發揮作用 大衛  這是我們唯一的希望
From the ashes of civilization, a small group of genetically unmodified individuals
在這片文明的廢墟上  一小群基因違背改造的人
established the Bureau of Genetic Welfare, here at Chicago's O'Hare airport.
建立了你們今天所在的這個基因福利局 在這兒 芝加哥的奧黑爾機場
You're safe.
你安全了
a grand experiment, to purify the human genome.
起目的就是淨化人類的基因組
You're safe now.
你現在安全了
Your destiny begins today.
你們的使命 從今天開始
Tris.
翠絲
In a moment of need, your mother did something
在危機關頭 你母親做了一件從
that no one had done before.
沒有人做過的事
She volunteered to leave the safety of the Bureau
她自願離開安全的基因局
to enter the experiment herself.
讓自己加入到實驗中
She did this because she knew the "damaged" were worth saving.
她做這些是因為她知道應該拯救缺陷者
She believed in the experiment so much she was willing to be a part of it.
她非常相信實驗所以她自願加入到實驗中
If I can show the Council your miracle can be replicated,
如果我讓委員會看到這個奇跡可以被複製
then her life's work is complete.
那麼她一生的工作就圓滿了
The Council will be force to look at any human being,
委員會不得不公平對待每個生命
No matter where they were born, is worthy of life.
不管他們來自哪裡，都有權利生存
Help me. You saved a city.
幫幫我 你救了一座城市
Help me save the world.
幫我拯救這個世界
It was amazing.
太不可思議了
It was like I was her and seeing it all through her eyes.
好像我變成了她，並通過她的眼睛看到了一切
I still can't believe my mom is from this place.
我還是不能相信我媽媽來自這兒
Well, I can see why she left.
我理解你媽媽為什麼要離開了
Do you trust him? David.
你相信他嗎，大衛？
I trust her.
我相信我媽媽
Yeah.
是的
Access denied.
禁止進入
Tris.
翠斯
Access granted.
允許進入
Here you are. You ready?
你來了，你準備好了嗎？
Say hi to David for me.
替我問候大衛
Tobias Eaton.
托比亞斯•伊頓
You've been assigned to me.
你分配到我的部門了
I am Nita. Let's go.
我是尼塔 ，我們走
Why isn't everyone allowed upstairs?
為什麼不是所有人都能上來
That would be one of the Council's many rules.
這是委員會重多規定中的一條
Certainly not mine.
我也沒辦法
The Separation, I don't like it.
這是隔離 我不喜歡
I agree, and in time, that won't be necessary.
我同意你的看法 這些到最後都是多餘的
第一時間更新中文字幕網
-= 字 幕 穀 論 壇 =-
But Tris, I don't know who told you that being different is a bad thing.
但是翠斯，我不知道是誰告訴你與眾不同是件壞事
Because I know it wasn't your mother.
因為我知道不是你母親
Now I know I can replicate this. All I need is time.
我知道能複製你的基因圖譜，只是時間問題
Look, Regina, let's talk. You seem like a nice lady, but...
聽著 雷吉納 我們得談談，你看上去像個好人
I'm really not a desk job kind of guy.
但我真的不適合坐辦公室工作
I get claustrophobic.
我有幽閉恐懼症
I need to be where the action is.
我得待在開放的地方
The job of Surveillance is to keep tabs
監視工作就要密切關注
on the developing situation in Chicago.
芝加哥日益動盪的局勢
This is where the action is.
這工作絕對放得開
Hayes, this will be your pod. Prior, you're next door.
海斯 這是你的監控室 普勒爾 你在隔壁的那間
Resistance is growing. Evelyn is beginning to respond.
抵抗日益激烈 伊芙琳是比會有所行動
Watch what's happening, file a report.
密切監視 然後提交報告
Wait. What... Hold on. I just escaped from Chicago.
等等 天哪 我剛從芝加哥逃出來
Now you're saying, I got to sit here and watch it
現在你卻要我後半輩子坐在這，監視它
for the rest of my life? With Caleb?
和它一起？
Perhaps you prefer to be banished to the Fringe?
也許你更願意被驅逐到邊界地帶
Ah. This Surveillance technology is incredible.
這兒的監控技術太不可思議了
- Whoever created it, is a genius. - Well, thank you.
造它的人一定是個天才  -謝謝你
It was a labor of love.
能熱愛你的工作
Ass kisser.
馬屁精
Keep it up, Prior.
把那個撿起來 普勒爾
And you, get to it.
還有你 開始工作
It's an awful lot of firepower.
火力夠充足的
The Fringe is full of dangerous people.
邊界地帶危機四伏
Put this on.
穿上這個
- What are these? - Personal drones.
這些是什麼？ -私人無人機
Expands your field of vision and provides 3D modeling and environments.
它能擴大視野，為你構建周圍環境的3D模型
Just like old times in Dauntless, huh?
就像過去在無畏派一樣，不是嗎？
Except there is nothing old about any of this.
除了沒有過時的東西以外
Here.
給你
Thanks.
謝謝
Activate the head gear.
啟動頭盔
The left hand activates the drones.
左手啟動無人機
[SCANNING]
ID: FOUR
Does it do anything else?
還能做別的嗎
Not much.
不太多
首發超清電影網
-= 字幕穀 www.zimugu.com =-
Use the drones to find the targets.
也就是用無人機找目標
It will take you a while to get the hang of it.
你需要花些時間才能熟悉它
Yeah.
是的
Okay.
好的
Identified.
目標確認
[SCANNING]
Target Identified.
目標已經確認
I think I got the hang of it.
我想我已經熟悉了
Can I ask you a question?
我能問你個問題？
- Yeah, of course. - If mother was born in the Fringe,
是的，當然 -如果我母親出生在邊界地帶
then, how did she end up in Chicago.
那她是怎麼到芝加哥的
I mean, you couldn't just sent her through the gate, right?
我是說你不可能把她送到了城門口吧？
No.
不是的
Now, the Council's always careful how they introduced any new element to the experiment.
委員會總是很謹慎的安置新人到實驗室，他們需要仲介人
Right. But, when they need to, they intervene.
仲介人需要時就會介入
Yes.
是的
So, why aren't they intervening now?
那為什麼現在還不介入呢？
They will. We just have to make our case.
他們會的 只要我們能說服他們
- Can I still count on you to help me? - Yes.
我能相信你會幫助我媽？ 當然
Can I count on you?
我能相信你媽？
Jeanine never had a chance against you.
珍妮是絕對沒有機會打倒你的
The sooner we get finished, the sooner we leave for Providence.
我們越快做好準備，就能越早去普羅維斯登
The Allegiant. That's what you're calling yourselves.
忠誠者，你們這麼稱呼自己
Amity just doesn't seem appropriate anymore.
友好派這個稱呼已經不再適合了
So, what exactly are you allegiant to? The faction system?
那麼你們到底忠誠於什麼？派別體系？
The factions kept Chicago peaceful for a long time.
派系在很長時間裡維持了芝加哥的和平
Well, I wouldn't know about that because I was forced out of my faction.
我並不瞭解這個，因為我被迫離開了派系
I gave up my life, my child, everything.
我放棄了我的生活，我的孩子，所有
I understand your anger, Evelyn, I do.
我理解你的憤怒 伊芙琳 真的
- But the way forward... - The way forward has already began.
但是未來的路 -未來的路已經鋪好了
I know I said I'd be alone, but...
我說過我會一個人來
I'm not Candor and I'm not Amity.
但我不是誠實派也不是友好派
So I will lie and I will fight if I have to.
所以我撒了謊 如果有必要的話我還會戰鬥
You see these scars? I wasn't born Amity.
看見這些傷疤了嗎？我不是出生在友好派
And I can assure you I'm not afraid to fight for what I believe in.
我能向你保證 我並不害怕為信念而戰
It seems like we're 2 peas in a pot.
看來我們是同一類人
But it doesn't have to be this way.
但並不一定非要這種方式
We can come to some sort of agreement.
我們可以好好商量
- Get back! - Get down!
退後 ！-趴下
- Get out of here! - Let's go.
離開這 -我們走
- Go! - Go.
快-快
Alright, Caleb.
聽著 凱萊布
Keep me posted if anything changes, alright?
萬一情況有變通知我好嗎？
- Hi. - Hey.
你好-你也是
Caleb said that some of the Dauntless are lining with Johanna.
凱萊布說無畏派的一些人站到了約翰娜這邊
But the rest of Candor are still solid with Evelyn.
但剩下的誠實派還和伊芙琳一個陣營
Things are  finally out of control.
局勢就快失去控制了
Did David say anything about what he can do?
大衛說過他能做什麼嗎？
Yeah, once we talk to the Council, then the Bureau can step in.
我們跟委員會談完 基因局會介入
So, it all hinges on the mysterious Council, does it?
所以這全靠神秘的委員會了 對吧？
- What if they say no? - David is confident that they won't.
他們不同意怎麼辦？ -大衛有信心說服他們
David, right.
大衛，好吧
You know, I found out why I can't go upstairs.
你知道，我搞清楚自己為什麼不能上去了
I'm "damaged", and you're "pure".
我是缺陷者 你是純淨者
I know.
我知道
You know. When were you going to tell me?
你知道 你打算什麼時候告訴我？
I don't know. I...
我不知道 我……
- I guess I didn't think that it matter. - Why doesn't it matter?
但我覺得這並不重要-為什麼不重要？
Because it doesn't make a difference if you're "pure" or  you're "damaged".
因為不管是純淨者還是缺陷者都沒什麼區別
You're still the same person to me.
對我來說你就是你
Look. I know that it's not perfect, by any means, but...
聽著 我知道無論如何它都不完美
The Bureau saved my mother from the Fringe. I wouldn't be here without her.
但基因局從邊界地帶救出了我媽媽，沒有他們我也不會再這兒
What do you actually know about what they do in the Fringe?
我們真的瞭解他們在哪兒做過什麼嗎？
You know what they tell you.
你只是聽他們說的
- Yeah, but... - I'm sorry.
是的 但是 -打擾下
He needs you upstairs.
他要你去樓上
他請你去樓上
Those people are nice, weird, but nice.
那些人恨友好，雖然奇怪 但很友好
Yeah. They're definitely weird, that's for sure.
是啊 他們的確很奇怪
You better get used to it.
你已經習慣了
- Really? - Yeah.
是嗎？ -沒錯
Next time you go to the Fringe, I want in.
下次去邊界地帶帶上我，我想加入
You're not ready.
你還沒準備好
I'm going.
我準備好了
Tris.
翠斯
I'm more than aware that the separation
我注意到分離對於你和老四來說很困難
has been difficult for you and Four, but...
I've watched you both enough to know that
但我已經觀察你們很久了
I think the two of you are going to work it out.
我想你們該解決下彼此之間的矛盾
We're fine.
我們很好
Everything's fine.
一直都很好
Good. Let's get to work.
好吧，我們去工作
Here we go! Fall in people!
我們走 大家集合
The weather's clear, we're green for a run!
天氣晴朗 執行逮捕行動
- You, let's go, let's go! - Come on, come on.
你們行動快點 我們走
- Move! Let's go! - Get ready to go!
我們走
Let's go!
Alright, here's the deal. Listen up!
好了 情況是這樣的 聽好了
This may be a Humanitarian mission,
這是一個人道主義任務
but the dwindle assembly is very dangerous.
但是林爾代據點非常危險
- Everybody clear? - Yes!
大家都聽清楚了嗎   -清楚
- So, what's the life span out here? - 25 to 30 years.
外面的人平均能活多久？  -25到30歲
But if we get people early, they can live up to 50 or 60 in the Bureau.
如果小時候就被救了，在基因局能活到50-60歲
Dauntless, if it's up to me, you would not be out here.
無畏派 如果是我就不會讓你們來這兒
I know you think it was tough in Chicago, but this is the Fringe.
我知道你們覺得芝加哥很危險
- Understood? - Yes.
聽懂了嗎？在這裡更加危險  -是的
The mission is to save as many kids as possible.
我們的任務是盡可能的救更多的孩子
They grow up in hellish conditions.
避免他們在惡劣的環境中長大
But, you have your weapons handy, you stick to protocol.
雖然你們手上有武器，但不要輕易使用
I don't want to lose any one.
我不想有任何傷亡
Get out your weapons.
帶上你們的武器
Come on, let's go!
來吧，進攻
Go! Go! Go. We got to move!
快  我們得行動了
Drones!
啟動無人機
Go!
走
Help!
幫幫我
Stop. Stop, stop. Hey, hey, hey. It's okay.
停下來 好了 沒事了 出去
I want my dad. Please!
放我下來 求你了
No! No! Dad!
不  不 不 爸爸
Everything will be fine. Let's go. Let's go.
沒事了  跟著我
Come on!
加油
Run!
跑
Searching Target.
目標搜索中
This way. This way.
這邊跑
Target identified.
目標已確認
Go!
快
- Stop! - Just stay away from us!
站在  離我們遠點兒
- Calm down. We're here to help. - We don't need your help.
冷靜點  我們是來幫你們的  -我們不需要你的説明
- I just want to talk to you. - I'm not going to lose my family!
我們想跟你談談  -我不想失去家人
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop!
站住 不要
-  Let go! Get away! - Get off him!
放開他  走開  別碰他
Get off him! Don't touch my boy!
別碰他  別碰我兒子
What did you do?
你做了什麼？
Come on. It's okay. It's alright.
來吧 沒事了
- I want to see my dad. - I know, I know.
我想見我爸爸 - 我知道
Four, let's go! We got to move!
老四   快走   我們撤
It's alright. It's okay.
沒事的  沒事了
Go! We got to go, we got to go.
我們走 快點兒
It's okay. Come on. Come on.
沒事了 跟我走
- Romit! - Don't.
羅米特  -讓開
What the hell is going on here?
究竟發生了什麼事
Just do you job, Dauntless.
做好你自己的事  無畏派
Let's go! Move!
我們走 快
Let's go!
我們走
One man, two children. Get them on the plane, go!
一個男人 2個小孩 抓住他們上飛機 ，快
Get back here!
回來
No!
不
I said, shut up. All of you.
閉嘴 你們都
- Hey. - You, stop!
你 站住
It's called a soap, you should try it.
這是香皂 你應該用用
What's up, Stiff? You lost?
怎麼了 僵屍人  迷路了？
I wanted to see Four.
我找老四
David and I are leaving for Providence.
大衛和我準備去普羅維凳斯
On a first name bases with the director, huh?
和關係親密的頭兒一起嗎
- You work fast. - Peter, can you leave her alone.
進展的挺快啊  皮特 別煩她了
I don't need you to defend me.
我不需要你幫我
Attention!
立正
Get us ready for Providence. I want my ship within an hour.
做好去普羅維登斯的準備
- Yes, sir. - Follow me.
是的 長官  -跟上我
David, hey.
大衛，嘿
I was wondering if I can talk to you about my job.
我在想是否我能和你談談我的工作
You know, I'm not really a typist and...
你知道 我真的不適合坐辦公室
Or if you are busy today, I get it.
如果你很忙  我能理解
Totally fine, we'll talk tomorrow.
沒事兒 我們明天再聊也行
Good idea.
好主意
Thank you.
謝謝
I need to talk to you.
我要跟你談談
What is this, Nita?
這是幹嘛 塔尼
Vaccinations.
打疫苗
What do you mean, vaccinations? We weren't given vaccinations.
什麼  打疫苗？我們幾個都沒打疫苗
Four.
老四
Look at this.
看看這個
Hey. What's your name?
嘿 你叫什麼名字
My name?
我的名字？
Hey.
嘿
- I'm sorry about your dad. - My dad?
你爸爸的事我很抱歉  -我爸爸？
- Alright, I'll see you back at base. - Yep.
好了  基因局總部見 -好的
This is not a humanitarian mission.
這不是人道主義任務
We're not saving kids, we're stealing them.
我們不是在救孩子 我們在綁架他們
This is what we do. Now you know.
這就是我們做的工作 現在你知道了
David takes them out from here,
大衛從這兒把他們帶走
wipes their memories with the gas, and raises them in the Bureau.
用記憶血清抹除他們的記憶，讓他們在基因局長大
If you take away what they know, then you take away who they are.
如果抹除了他們的記憶，也就抹掉了他們的身份
Yeah. I think that's the point.
沒錯 這就是目的
They were all unarmed.
他們都沒有武器
I won't surrender to this.
我不會因此投降的
Round up anyone who's left.
看看還有沒有活著的
We take the fight to Evelyn.
我們要跟伊芙琳開戰
Yeah. I'm loading up.
好 我去裝車
Let's go.
我們走
Move it.
移開這個
Today we take Evelyn down!
今天我們要打倒伊芙琳
Whatever it takes!
不惜一切代價
This is all real time.
這是現場直播
I mean, this Surveillance Technology they have in place is extraordinary.
我們在這兒的監控技術簡直了得
Caleb, can you get out of your head for a second?
凱萊布 能別想自己的事兒嗎？
This is our home.
那兒是我們的家
There's going to be a war.
那兒就要開戰了
Where are you going?
你要去哪兒？
I'm going to do something about it.
得為芝加哥做點什麼
Four, what are you trying to do?
老四  你這是要去幹什麼
Getting Tris. We're leaving.
我去找翠斯 我們得離開
You can't go up there.
你不能上去
- What do you think you are doing? - Four!
你知道自己在幹什麼嗎?  -老四
- You cannot be in here. - Four.
你不能在這兒  -老四
- It's not going to work. - Pure.
這麼做沒用的    純淨
Central elevator has been compromised.
中央電梯被入侵了
- Hey. - We're leaving.
嘿  -我們得離開這兒
- What? - Right now.
什麼？ -馬上
What? I can't.
什麼？我不能走
You don't understand yet, but these people have been lying to you.
聽著 你還不瞭解情況 這些人在騙你
Lying? What are you talking about?
騙局？你在說什麼？
Look, whatever they told you. They've been...
聽著 不管他們說什麼 其實他們……
Put the guns down.
放下武器
He's been stealing children from their families.
這個大衛他一直都在搶別人的孩子
We're giving them a better life.
我們給了他們更好的生活
- By killing their parents? - It was an unfortunate accident. Sir.
就因此殺了他們父母？  -那只是個意外 長官
One terrible accident doesn't mean that it was the wrong thing to do.
一個可怕的意外不代表這麼做是錯的
Tris, This is not the place that we thought it was suppose to be.
翠斯 這個地方跟我們想的不一樣
If you have enough to save one person,
如果你有能力去救一個人
and your choice was between a healthy child or a sick old man,
你選擇救健康的孩子 還是救生病的老人
- who would you choose? - I wouldn't choose!
你選誰 我不會選擇
Good, now they're both dead.
好吧  那他們都會死
We have to go.
我們得走了
Tris. We're going back to Chicago, we shouldn't ever have left.
翠斯 我們得回芝加哥去  我們從沒離開過
- No, we have to wait. - Yeah, we've been waiting.
不 我們得再等等 -是的  我們一直在等待
Okay, David is not the person that you think he is.
大衛根本就不是你想的那種人
Four, you know nothing about David.
老四 你不瞭解大衛
You've no idea what we've been working up here.
你不瞭解我們都在這兒忙什麼
What have you been working on?
你們忙些什麼？
Do you have any idea what is going on out there?
你知道芝加哥現在發生什麼了嗎？
Yes, of course I do.
知道 我當然知道
Why do you think we're going to meet with the Council?
這就是我們為什麼要去見委員會的人？
Tris.
翠斯
I want you to listen to me.
我求你認真聽我說 翠斯
Tris.
翠斯
You're coming with me.
跟我回去
I have to go.
我得走了
You're making a mistake.
你犯了一個錯誤
You ready?
你準備好了？
Yeah.
是的
Autopilot engage.
啟動自動駕駛儀
You want to go back to Chicago, I'll take you.
你想回芝加哥 我載你
No, thanks.
不 謝謝
You want to walk cross the Fringe, I don't think so.
就這麼走著穿越邊界地帶
There's no rule saying you can't go home, Four.
沒有規定說你不能走 老四
Come on.
跟我來
- Yeah. - I'll go with you.
好吧  -我跟你們去
All set.
準備就緒
Take us to Chicago.
帶我們去芝加哥
Look, I understand how you're feeling. But...
聽著  我能理解你的感受
What you're about to do has ramifications for people all over the world.
但是你現在要做的事對全世界而言將產生巨大的影響
If Four doesn't see that, it's not your fault.
如果老四不理解 也不要往心裡去
David never wanted you to see what you saw, out on the Fringe.
大衛根本不想讓你看到邊界地帶的事
He keeps tight control. Nothing happens without his approval.
他一直嚴格控制 他沒允許我們這麼做
And his ship, is the only one that can fly through the camo wall.
他的飛船是唯一可以穿越偽裝牆的
Why are you telling me this?
為什麼告訴我這些
We are not taking you to Chicago.
我們不會送你去芝加哥
Hold on!
抓緊
Welcome to Providence.
歡迎來到普羅維斯登
I can see why they don't want to share it.
明白他們為什麼不願意分享了
Some day, the whole world is going to look this beautiful.
有一天全世界都會像這兒一樣美
So, as you can see, there are multiple
如諸位所知的，有多種基因標記可以支撐這個結論
genetic markers supporting this conclusion.
Standard personality test. Behavioral evaluations. Stimulus response.
標準性格測試 行為評估 刺激反應
She's passed them all with flying colors.
她輕易的通過了所有的測試
It all sounds great assuming it's the truth.
如果這是真的 聽起來確實不錯
Phillip.
菲力浦
David has lied to us before, haven't you, David?
大衛以前騙過我們 不是嗎 大衛？
I like to hear from the girl.
讓這個女孩說說
Well, I don't know why she can't tell you anything I'm not.
要知道 她可不會為了我而撒謊
Indulge us, David.
幫個忙 大衛
This must all come as quite a shock to you, Miss Prior,
發現自己是分歧者（純潔者）對你來說一定很吃驚吧 普勒爾小姐
finding out that you are pure
Um.
嗯
Pure. I'm not even sure what's that suppose to mean.
純潔者 我甚至都不知道是什麼
But yes, it is shocking to me.
沒錯 我很吃驚
Shocking that the more I learn about the past, the more I feel like...
我對過去了解更多就越感到
you're all making the same mistakes over and over again.
你們好像一直在犯同一個錯誤
- Tris, this is not the way. - Let her speak, David.
翠斯 別這麼說 -讓她繼續 大衛
What mistakes, Tris?
什麼錯誤 翠斯？
The human beings cannot be categorized in this way.
人類不能用這種方法進行分類
It doesn't work.
這是沒用的
Maybe it's time to start embracing everyone instead of dividing them into groups.
也許是時候接受所有人了，而不是把他們分在不同的群體裡
Regardless whether they are 'pure' or they are 'damaged'.
無論他們是純潔者還是缺陷者
- That isn't what we're here to discuss. - Well, it should be.
這不是我們要討論的問題  -是的
Look, I know that all of this is just an experiment to you,
聽著 我知道一切對你們來說是一項實驗
but these people in Chicago are real.
但對芝加哥的人民來說缺是真實的
And they're in a war right now because of divisions that you created,
你們創建的派系導致他們現在仍生活在戰亂裡
and you are doing nothing to help them.
你們卻坐視不管
David has control over the administration of Chicago.
你要知道大衛才是掌握芝加哥管理權的人
He's only here to extend his funding.
他來這兒只是為了增加他的經費
Which, we would be happy to do,
我們樂於做某些事
but if things are as bad as she says, David.
但如果真像她說的那麼差勁 大衛
Shouldn't you get your house in order first?
你難道不應該先回家呆著嗎？
You said that you couldn't do anything.
你跟我說過你無能為力
I am doing something. I'm bring back the factions.
我在行動了  我在重建派別制度
What? Why?
什麼？為什麼？
I hope the Allegiant will take care of the problem for me.
我希望忠誠者能為我解決這個問題
The factions work, Tris.
派系是有用的 翠斯
They keep the peace, they created you.
它們維護了和平 成就了你
I never should have trusted you.
我真不應該相信你
You want change with no sacrifice, you want peace with no struggle.
你不想犧牲就革命，你想不鬥爭就迎來和平
The world doesn't work like that.
這個世界不是這樣的
You okay?
你還好嗎？
I'll be fine.
我沒事
I hope the Bureau isn't far.
快到基因局了
I need to get to Chicago, and tell Evelyn
我想回芝加哥 告訴伊芙琳她犯的錯比約翰娜更嚴重
she's got a lot bigger problem than Johanna.
You'll need this, to get through the camo wall.
你需要這個才能穿越偽裝牆
We need your help, Tobias.
我們需要你的説明 托比亞斯
You don't know what he's capable of.
你不瞭解大衛的真面目
What about Tris?
翠斯怎麼樣了
As long as she stays in the Bureau, she's safe.
只要呆在基因局 她就是安全的
She's too valuable to him.
她對大衛來說很重要
I'll need a head start.
我要先考慮下
When David asks,
如果大衛聞起來
I want you to tell him that I left you behind.
你就跟他說我背叛了你們
Okay?
好嗎？
- Why? - Because Tris will know you're lying.
為什麼？ -因為翠斯會知道你在說謊
SCANNING
PURE @ MATTHEW.B ACCESS GRANTED
純淨派 馬修•B 允許通行
There was an accident.
出了點事
There was turbulence, not more than any other storm, but...
遇到一股氣流，雖然沒有風暴厲害，也許有閃電
The lightning, maybe.
也許有閃電
- We just went down. - Where's Four?
接著飛機就墜毀了 老四呢？
I don't know.
我不知道
I passed out, when I cam to, everyone was dead.
我失去意識了  當我醒來的時候所有人都死了
Four left me behind.
老四丟下了我
Okay, we search the settlement, search the Fringe.
好吧  找找那些據點
Make sure he's not there.
確定他在不在那兒
Don't worry. We'll find him, I promise.
別擔心 我們會找到他的 我保證
Four would never leave anyone behind at the crash site.
老四是絕對不會出了意外後丟下任何人的
Yeah. He told me you would say that.
是的  他跟我說過你一定會這麼說
Four is trying to make his way back to Chicago.
老四這會兒在回芝加哥的路上
- Peter. - Hello, David.
皮特 -你好，大衛
I didn't think that you knew my name.
我以為你不知道我的名字
I know all of the important people from Chicago.
我瞭解所有芝加哥來的重要人物
Really?
真的？
Well, if I'm so important,
那麼 我是重要人物了
then why did you give me such a terrible job?
為什麼你還讓我幹那麼爛的活兒
We all have to make sacrifices.
我們都得做出一些犧牲
I don't see you making any.
你犧牲了？
Peter.
皮特
I need help with something in Chicago.
我需要芝加哥那邊有人幫我
What's in it for me?
我有什麼好處？
Well, if you do well, you can have any job you want.
如果完成不錯 工作隨便你挑
Except mine.
除了我的
Do you know where Peter is ?
知道皮特在哪兒嗎？
Uh, he's not in his pod?
嗯 他不在監控室嗎？
No.
沒有
No, I don't know where he is.
那就不知道了
Is there something that I can help you with?
有什麼需要幫忙的嗎？
Can you find Four?
你能找到老四
You can't tell anyone.
你不能告訴別人
Okay, of course.
當然
Anything you need, Beatrice.
都聽你的 碧翠斯
Come on, Four, where are you?
快點兒 老四  你在哪兒？
Evelyn. We found him outside the wall.
伊芙琳 我們在圍牆外發現了他
Take it off.
把面罩拿下
Where's my son?
我兒子在哪兒？
I don't know.
我不知道
Edgar told me what's out there.
埃德告訴了我圍牆外的情況
So you better start talking, or we'll be holding your trial now!
所以你最好說點什麼，否則我會馬上就審判你
No, you won't.
不  你不會的
Because I have something that you need.
因為我有你想要的東西
Really? And what's that?
真的？是什麼？
The way to win your war.
贏得戰爭的勝利的方法
- Hey. - Hey.
嘿  - 嘿
Any news?
有消息？
No.
沒有
I'm sorry.
對不起
Tris!
翠斯
- Did you find him? - Yes, I found Four.
你在找他？  -是的，我找到老四了
And there's something else you're going to want to see too.
你還是過來看看吧
Okay, go.
好的，來吧
Over there! That's him! We got him!
在那兒，就是他 發現他了
Four.
老四
Don't worry, he's fine. Just... keep watching.
別擔心 他很好，只是……繼續看
What is this place?
那是什麼地方？
You're going to love it.
你會愛上它的
What is it?
這是什麼
Try it out. You'll see.
試一下 就知道了
Just don't try it on anyone you like.
別用在你喜歡的人身上
I was wondering when you'll have the courage to face me.
我一直在想你什麼時候才有勇氣面對我
3 weeks you leave me here.
我在這兒已經三個星期了
I run a faction!
我管理著一個派系
I protected our son from Jeanine's thugs.
我保護我們的兒子不受珍妮的迫害
Protected him. Is that what you call it?
你保護他  這就叫保護？
Beating your own child.
暴打你自己的孩子
It made him who he is.
這才成就了今天的他
Make sure he gets a good dose.
注意控制下劑量
Tobias, I was trying to make you to be better.
托比亞斯 我這麼做只想讓你變得更好
I'm-I'm sorry, but...
對不起 但是……
Who you are?
可是你是誰？
Just imagine if you release this on the Allegiant.
想像一下把這個用在忠誠者身上
Not even Johanna will remember a time that you weren't in charge.
甚至連約翰娜都不會記得你曾經不是這裡的領導者
Who exactly told you about this?
這個東西是誰給你的
You have a very powerful friend on the outside,
你在牆外面有個很厲害的朋友
if you choose to engage instead of prepare.
只要你選擇合作而不是反抗
- Does this friend have a name? - David.
這位朋友叫什麼名字？ -大衛
David?
大衛？
You can tell my friend I'm not going to use that thing unless it's the last resort.
你可以告訴我這位的朋友，不到最後一刻我是不會用這個東西的
Why would David support Evelyn?
大衛為什麼要支持伊芙琳？
It doesn't make any sense.
完全沒道理
Are you okay? I was worried about you.
你還好嗎？我很擔心你
Evelyn, you need to make peace with the Allegiant.
伊芙琳 你跟忠誠者講和
No, Johanna made her choice. I never wanted this war.
不 約翰娜已經做出了選擇。我從沒想過發動戰爭
But I will end it, I promise you.
我會結束它的。我保證
You have no idea what you are up against.
你都不知道你的敵人是誰
- Johanna is not the issue. - Look.
約翰娜不是問題的關鍵 -聽著
I know you're angry at me and I understand that.
我知道你還在生我的氣
I'm just... I never meant...
我只是……我從沒想到……
This is so hard for me too.
現在對我來說也很艱難
I don't want to have to keep you in here.
我心裡也不想把你關在這兒
Then, let me out.
那麼 放我出去
I can't, I have responsibilities.
我做不到 因為這是我的責任
One day, you'll understand that, but right now I need you to stay here.
總有一天你會理解我的，但是你現在必須待在這兒
I'm going to finish this. One way or another.
我會結束一切的，無論發生什麼
How are you going to finish this?
你打算怎麼結束這一切？
Hey, don't worry. You won't have to be here for long.
別擔心 你不會待太久的
What-What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
Well, Evelyn is deciding now,
伊芙琳還在拿主意
If she use the memory serum, Chicago might forget it's own name.
如果她使用記憶血清，所有人都會忘了自己是誰
We have to go.
我們得走了
Get Christina and meet me outside.
腳上克莉絲蒂娜 在外面碰頭
Where are we going?
我們要去哪兒？
Home.
回家
Access granted.
允許進入
How's it going in Chicago?
芝加哥那邊怎麼樣了？
Making sure it's safe from Evelyn and the factionless?
確定伊芙琳她們沒有危險的舉動？
Tris.
翠斯
You need to forget about Chicago.
你要忘掉芝加哥
You know, it's really funny, David.
你知道，你真是可笑 大衛
You've been watching me for years and you don't know anything about me.
你觀察我這麼多年卻一點都不瞭解我
You're wiping the memories of everyone in Chicago, aren't you?
你打算清楚芝加哥城裡所有人的記憶
- Alright. Uh... - You were never supporting the Allegiant.
沒錯 -你根本就不支持忠誠者
These people treated you terribly, they killed your parents.
別忘了這些人背叛了你，他們殺了你的父母
- Four is there! - Oh, Four.
老四在那裡 -哦 老四
Yes. Yes. Four is there.
是的  老四在那兒
But he's "damaged", just like the rest of them.
但是他是缺陷者，跟其他人是一樣的
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
I'm taking your ship and I'm not come back.
坐你的飛船離開  不會再回來了
You can't fly.
你不會開
Watch me.
看好了
Autopilot engage.
啟動自動駕駛儀
Tris Prior is stealing my craft, bring her back.
翠斯•普勒爾偷走了我的飛船，抓她回來
Hurry.
快
- Cristina, these are for you and Tris. - How did you know we were leaving?
克莉絲蒂娜，這是給你和翠斯的 -你怎麼知道我們要走？
You're not the only ones who hate David.
不是只有你一個人恨大衛
- Hey, come on! - Thank you.
嘿，快點兒 -謝謝你
- Hold it! - Get in, get in.
接住！進來
Hands to yourself or I'll throw you out.
把你的手拿開  不然把你扔出去
Let's go rescue Four.
我們去救老四
Looks like 3 ships are following us.
有三艘飛船跟蹤我們
- Plasma craft engaged. - Surround her.
包圍住 -使他迫降
Give her a nudge towards the ground. The autopilot will bring her down safely.
自動駕駛儀能讓飛船安全著陸
What are they trying to do?
他們想幹什麼？
They're trying to bring us in for a landing!
他們想讓我們迫降
I'm going manual!
我換手操作
- Pull up! Pull up! - I'm trying!
拉起來 -我在努力
I'm trying!
我在努力
Altitude
注意高度
I got it.
成功了
Your order, sir?
請下令 長官
Shoot her down.
把她的飛船擊落
Before she reaches the camo wall. You can't follow her through.
在她到達偽裝牆之前
We're dead.
我們死定了
We're gonna die! We're gonna die!
我們死定了……
Hold on.
抓穩了
We're getting close!
我們快到了
- Ho! - Whoa!
呼……
There has to be a way to shut off the gas.
一定可以阻止記憶血清的擴散
Look at the ventilation system, it's all over the city.
看看遍佈城市的通風系統
Down there.
看那兒
Johanna.
約翰娜
We got here just in time.
我們正來的是時候
It's time, Evelyn.
是時候了，伊芙琳
You said, the gas was a last resort.
你說過記憶血清是你的最後一招
Well?
是嗎？
How do think your trial is going to end?
你認為對你的審判會是什麼結果？
Let me know the second the serum is released.
血清一旦釋放就立刻通知我
You got it. Good luck.
明吧 祝你好運
Thank you.
謝謝
How do these drones work?
這無人機怎麼用？
Turn your headgear on.
戴上頭盔
- And? - Watch and learn.
然後？ -看著學
Stop right there and drop your weapons!
站住 放下武器
Hey, hey! Whoa! Hey, what are you doing?
嘿 嘿！你們要幹什麼？
Put me down!
放我下去
Alright, this one is on you.
好了  這個交給你
- Easy! - Sorry!
小心-抱歉！
Stay where you are!
站住不許動
That's my girl.
幹得漂亮
Recon.
偵查
Screw this! I'm out of here!
這是什麼鬼 我不幹了
What the hell is that?
這是什麼玩意兒
Hey.
嘿
I'm sorry.
對不起
I never should have trusted him.
我不該相信他的
You do what you thought was right.
你只是做了你認為對的事
I love you.
我愛你
We should find Evelyn.
我們得找到伊芙琳
Come on.
走吧
Serum Status: Ready.
血清準備就緒
Now.
現在
If you press that button,
如果你按下按鈕
We're complete safe inside the vault.
我們在地下室是絕對安全的
And...
而且
No one else will ever know what happen to them.
沒人知道發生了什麼
Your choice.
自己選吧
Initialize: Serum vaporization
血清氣化啟動
Guys. Guys. They just initiated the serum.
夥計們 他們啟動了血清氣化程式
Did you find a way to shut it off?
找到關閉方法了嗎
Not yet.
還沒有
This way.
這邊走
It's locked.
鎖住了
I'll see if I can get into the Control room.
我看看能不能從控制室打開它
Evelyn, you have to stop this right now.
伊芙琳 你現在必須馬上關了它
I...
我
I do want to do this, but I have to.
我本不想這樣 但我別無選擇
I'm the only one who knows how to save Chicago.
我是唯一知道如何拯救芝加哥的人
I was right to close the gate, but no one listened!
我關上城門是對的 但是沒有人聽
No one!
沒有人
Not even you.
連你也不聽
The Allegiant, brought this on themselves.
這都是忠誠者他們逼我這麼幹的
Evelyn, that serum is not just going to wipe the memories of the Allegiant.
伊芙琳 記憶血清不光會清除忠誠者們的記憶
It's going to do it to the whole city.
還會清除所有人的記憶
What?
什麼
Whatever they told you was a lie.
那些人是騙你的
What...
我沒有
- Come on - Evelyn.
我不能 伊芙琳
I want to stand by your side.
我來是想幫你的
But what you do to the city...
如果城市被你毀了
... you do to me.
我也一樣
Mom.
媽媽
Tobias.
托比亞斯
I won't know who you are.
我會想不起你是誰
Don't do it.
停手吧
Please.
求你了
Going.
快點兒
No!
不
That's why he picked a guy like me for a job like this.
你選擇我這樣的真是個明智之舉
I hope you're watching, David!
我希望你正在看著 大衛
Cristina, have you figured out the door yet?
克瑞斯蒂娜 找到開門的方法了嗎
Once it's locked from the inside, the door won't open.
門一旦從裡面上鎖就打不開了
Well, keep trying!
再試試
Begin serum release.
開始釋放血清
Don't breathe it in! Don't breathe in the gas!
不要吸入這些氣體
Caleb, we're running out of option here!
凱勒布 我們現在走投無路了
Hold on. I think I found something.
淡定 我想我找到辦法了
There's a choke point where the vapor gets pumped out.
這兒有個氣體擴散的咽喉點
Cut their comm line to the ship.
切斷他們之間的無線電
Caleb?
凱勒布
- Caleb? - Tris?
凱勒布 翠絲
Tris, can you hear me?
翠絲 聽得到嗎
Caleb!
凱勒布
I'm going in.
我要進去了
What!
臥槽
Oh shit!
我了個大槽
What the...
什麼情況
- Make it stop! - It's locked!
快關上它 鎖住了
- Open the door! - Open the door!
開門呐 開門呐
Peter, open the door!
彼得 快開門呐
I will find you, Peter.
彼得 我會抓住你的
Tobias.
托比亞斯
You're okay.
沒事兒了
Damn it!
該死
- Can you stop it? - No.
能關掉嗎 不行
Caleb, do you hear me?
凱勒布 聽得到嗎
Caleb, where are you?
凱勒布 你死哪兒去了
Caleb Prior!
凱勒布•普勒特
Sorry.
抱歉
Keep going. Stay with me.
繼續走 跟上
Tris, look at this. It's really smart.
翠絲 看看這個 非常精確
So, they ran the pipe into the air duck.
它們順著通風管在空氣中擴散
Caleb, focus. Just tell me where it is.
凱勒布 說重點 薄弱點在哪兒
It's right here. There's an isolation valve that controls the flow of the air.
就在這兒 這兒有個獨立閥門控制空氣流通
But, I don't know how you're going to get down there.
但我不知道怎麼去那兒
I do. Four!
我來 老四
Go!
行動
Tris, it's at the end of the hall.
翠絲 在走廊的盡頭
Close the doors.
關門
Tris, I control everything.
翠絲 我控制著一切事物
I can even seal the room you're in right now.
我甚至能立刻把你鎖在這個房間裡
Just stop fighting.
直到你停止反抗
There's another way. Down the stairs.
還有一條路 下樓梯
This is foolish, just stop. I made you.
蠢蛋 快停下吧 我造就了你
You might as well be my child. Which is what you're acting like.
你就像我的孩子一樣 你現在的一舉一動
A spoil child.
淘氣的沒邊兒了
Tris, at the end of the hall. There's another way on the left.
翠絲 在走廊的盡頭 有另一條路通往梯子那兒
It's over, Tris.
都結束了 翠絲
Searching target.
搜索目標
Target identified.
目標已確認
There you are.
找到了
You're right, David. It is over.
大衛 你說得對 都結束了
NO!
不
Serum release halted.
血清釋放終止
How's that for "damaged".
缺陷者表現如何
Clear.
安全
It's clear.
乾淨了
It's not here.
氣體沒了
Clear.
安全
We did it.
成功了
That's what you do for family.
這才是該為家人做的
Caleb, there's one more thing I want you to do.
凱勒布 我想讓你再幫我做件事兒
I want to send a message to David.
我想給大衛發條信息
My name Tris Prior.
我是翠絲•普勒爾
And I'm here to reveal the truth.
我今天在這兒要揭露一個真相
There are others who exist on this planet
這個星球上確實有其他人類存在
They do not view us as equals.
可他們沒有平等對待我們
They called themselves the "Pure", and they called us the "damaged".
他們稱自己為純淨者 稱我們為缺陷者
They created a wall to divide us from their world.
他們用圍牆將我們與他們隔離開來
And factions to divide us from each other.
用派系將我們彼此分開
Hello! Come on!
有人嗎 得了吧
You think you can ditch me like this?
你認為這樣就能夠把我一腳踢開是嗎
You got me to do your dirty work
讓我幫你做那些缺德事兒
and then just, wiped me away like the rest of them!
然後像甩他們一樣把我甩掉
We had a deal, pal!
我們不是說好了嗎 朋友
We're their experiment, and it almost destroyed us.
我們成了試驗品 這幾乎毀了我們
I set the autopilot right for our friend's neighbourhood.
我把自動駕駛儀設在了我們朋友附近
Along with a little surprise when it goes through the camouflage wall.
當它穿越偽裝牆的時候 會給他們一個小小的驚喜
They tried to make us forget who we are
他們企圖讓我們忘記自己是誰
and where we're from, but they did not succeed.
來自何方 但他們沒有成功
So, here we stand together,
所以我們能站在這兒團結一致
not as 5 factions, but as one city.
不是作為五大派系 而是作為一座城市
We're gonna tear down their wall.
我們要推翻他們建立的圍牆
Hey. What's going on?
嘿 那是什麼玩意兒
I want the penthouse!
我想住頂樓
Yeah, that's right!
是的 沒錯
Or...
或者
a room in that really cool upstairs area.
跟上面一樣酷的房間也行
Okay, look!
好吧 聽著
I'll even take my old bunk back!
我會回到我以前住的地方的
Just come on and open the damn door!
只要快點兒把這該死的門打開
Please!
求你了
You've seen us, and now, we see you.
過去你們看著我們 現在我們看著你們
To those of you beyond the wall,
牆外的人們
hear me loud and clear, because I know you are listening.
你們現在聽好了 我知道你們正在聽
Chicago is not your experiment.
芝加哥不是你們的實驗室
It is our home.
是我們的家園
And it always will be.
永遠都是